At this point, you may be wondering,
现在你可能会疑问
well, what causes volatility anyway?
到底是什么导致了波动率？
A natural assumption may be that volatility of
我们很自然地认为波动率
a stock is caused by new information reaching the market.
可能是由进入市场的新信息导致的
New information causes people to revise their opinions about the value of a stock.
新的信息导致人们重新审视股票的价值
The price of the stock changes which causes volatility.
股价变化导致波动率
However, research hasn't supported this conclusion.
但是 研究并没证实这种结论
Research studies have compared the variance of stock price returns between
一些调查研究比较了某一天的收盘价
the closing price on one day and the closing price on the next trading day,
与下个交易日（中间没有非交易日）的
when there are no non-trading days in between,
收盘价股价收益率方差
and the closing price on a Friday and the closing price on a Monday.
以及周五的收盘价与周一的收盘价股价收益率方差
You might expect the weekend variance to be
你可能认为周末的方差
three times the midweek variance because the real elapsed time is three times as long.
是工作日方差的三倍 因为真实的时差是三倍
However, this has not been found to be the case,
但实际上并非如此
even for assets affected by news that is equally
甚至某些资产即使受到在工作日出现
likely to arrive midweek or on a weekend.
和在周末出现的概率是一样的新闻影响 也如此
The weekend variants of orange juice futures prices which are mainly affected by
橙汁期货价格（主要受到天气新闻的影响）的
weather news is only about 1.5 times the midweek variance.
周末方差仅仅约为工作日方差的 1.5 倍
The implication of all this is that volatility is,
所有这些表明
to a large extent,
从很大程度上来说
caused by trading itself.
波动率是由交易本身导致的
This idea is consistent with the observation
这种观点与
that volatility and volume are frequently correlated.
波动率和成交量经常相关这种现象保持一致
All other things being equal,
所有其他项保持相同的话
greater trading volume means greater volatility.
成交量越大 波动率就越大
But during a time when volatility is high because
但是当成交量很大并且价格上涨
lots of trading is happening and the price goes up,
导致波动率很高时
you might reasonably expect the price to go back down.
你可能会合理地认为价格将回落
If there was no news,
如果没有新闻
the price probably didn't increase because the company's performance improved.
价格上涨很可能不是因为公司的业绩改善了
It probably increased because people wanted to trade large numbers of
而是因为人们想交易大量股票
stocks and sellers charged a premium for that ability to trade, or liquidity.
而卖方针对这种交易能力或流动性收取了费用
This means that for equity strategies in high volatility times,
所以 在高波动率时期
a type of strategy considered more likely to do well is a type of strategy based on
有一种股权策略更有可能表现很好
the idea that prices will return to their running mean when they go way up or down.
这种策略认为当股价上涨或下跌幅度很大时 它们会回到均值上
These are called mean reversion strategies.
称为均值回归策略
In low volatility times,
在低波动率时期
momentum strategies may work better.
动量策略可能业绩更好
There are other general patterns in market behavior with respect to volatility.
市场行为还有与波动率相关的其他基本规律
One is that market volatility tends to be high when
一个规律是当市场下跌时 波动率会变高
the market is going down and low when the market is going up.
当市场上涨时 波动率会变低
Because of this, volatility is often quoted in the popular media as the gauge for fear.
所以 大众媒体经常将波动率称作恐惧指数
To see this most clearly,
举个例子
let's look at an index that essentially measures market volatility.
我们来看一个专门衡量市场波动率的指数
You might have heard of the VIX Index,
你可能听过 VIX 指数
which is a market index measuring the volatility of 30-day S&amp;P 500 Index options.
它是一个衡量 30 天标普 500 指数期权波动率的市场指标
The value of the VIX index represents the annualized volatility of the S&amp;P 500 Index.
VIX 指数的值表示标普 500 指数的年化波动率
This plot of the VIX Index and S&amp;P 500 Index over
这是相同时期的 VIX 指数和标普 500 指数图表
the same periods shows that the VIX spikes when the S&amp;P dips.
从图中可以看出 当标普 500 达到低谷时 VIX 指数达到峰值
For example, between 1990 and 2015,
例如 从 1990 到 2015 年
VIX spiked to a record 80 during October and November of 2008 when,
VIX 在 2008 年 10 月和 11 月达到破纪录的 80
as you remember, the markets were roiling from a huge crisis.
而当时的市场出现了严重的金融危机
I know what you're thinking,
我知道你在想
can you trade the VIX itself?
能直接交易 VIX 指数吗？
You guessed it. Humans will turn anything into tradeable securities.
你猜对了人们可以将任何东西变成可交易的证券
You can trade futures and options on the VIX Index which
你可以针对 VIX 指数交易期货和期权
essentially amounts to making a bet on the volatility of the S&amp;P 500.
也就是对标普 500 的波动率下赌注
The VIX is published by the Chicago Board Options Exchange,
VIX 由芝加哥期权交易所发行
which publishes a range of other volatility indices on stock
芝加哥期权交易所还发行了
and commodity indices currencies and some individual stocks.
一系列关于股票 商品指数 货币和其他单个股票的波动率指数
There's even a Volatility Index of the VIX Index, the VVIX.
甚至还有一个 VIX 指数的波动率指数 称为 VVIX